The
Villanova wild cats.
[ APPLAUSE ]
The Villanova wild cats.
&gt;&gt; Ladies and gentlemen, the
president of the United States.
Accompanied by coach Wright.
[ APPLAUSE ]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everybody.
Hello!
Everybody, please have a seat.
Welcome to the White House.
And I guessth blue and White
House today because we're giving
it up to the 2016 NCAA champions
Villanova wild cats!
[ APPLAUSE ]
[ CHEERING ]
You should know that we have
some big fans here from both
sides of the aisle in congress.
We also want to acknowledge the
Villanova president who's here.
[ APPLAUSE ]
Athletic director Mark Jackson
who camped off his first year
with a national championship.
Pretty good job.
Pretty good.
[ APPLAUSE ]
Unfortunately perhaps the --
most important nova grad here Dr
Dr. Joe Biden could not be here.
She may be teaching but her
husband Joe wanted me to remind
you that he picked nova to win
it all.
[ APPLAUSE ]
This is the type of wise council
that you're looking from a vice
president.
Unfortunately I didn't follow
his council so my bracket was
busted.
We have the best dressed man in
college basketball.
[ CHEERING ]
The George Cloony of coaches Jay
Wright and today we celebrate a
remarkable team that worked
tirelessly to make the coach
look good in terms of his job
and not just his wardrobe.
His Taylor could not make it but
we have his basketball players
here.
So coach Wright and this team
treated us to as memorable a run
and as memorable a championship
game as I can remember.
We'll talk more about that game
in a second but these wild cats
were about more than just one
moment or one shot.
She had unbelievable defense.
They had great clutch shooting.
A senior class that won more
games than any group in wild cat
history.
They had a stable of talent
players who are as happy
on the
deck as they were cutting down
the nets.
He became just the 7th player
in program history to score 1,
1,000 points and grab 900 boards
boards.
Pretty good.
[ APPLAUSE ]
Also not afraid to do the little
thing.
We grabbed the mop in the middle
of the game.
We have josh Hart who led in
scoreing.
Congratulations.
Where did you go to school?
Bidwell friends school.
[ APPLAUSE ]
My daughter will be graduateing
from there next week which makes
me cry when I talk about it so
I'm not going to talk about it
but it's good to see you do well
well.
Chris Jenkens aka big smooth.
[ APPLAUSE ]
Learned how to shoot from his
mom.
Moms know what they are talking
about and then there is Ryan.
Now I just sped through that in
case I didn't say it right.
Barack Obama is tough but -- man
that is a lot of vowels in there
there.
So we're going to call it --
wore the blue and white in more
games than any wild cat ever and
went out in style as the most
outstanding player of the final
four so we're very, very proud
of hip.
Give him a round of applause.
[ APPLAUSE ]
But more than any individual
honor this team possessed
something that the coaches
preached from day one and that
is attitude.
As coach Wright said in life you
cannot control what happens to
you but you do control how you
respond to it and this is how
they bounceed back from dis
disappointing tournaments.
That is how they rolled through
the first three rounds by an
average of 24 points.
Beat Kansas to punch their
ticket to the final four.
They blew the doors off Oklahoma
by
44 point margin which set up
the unbelievable showdown with
the Tarheels.
Might be the best title game of
all-time.
Just last few seconds could be a
documentary.
You had an unbelievable double
clutch circus shot from Marcus
Paige.
A lot of teams would have had
their spirit broken.
Wild cats, they took control and
they responded and on a play
called nova Chris took the pass
from marks and pulled up a few
steps and shot this team into
basketball lore.
This was a good shot.
And it was like a Christian
Lleyton shot.
A Jimmy v running up and down
the court shot.
Charles Barkley apparently
jumped out of his seat which he
doesn't do very often these days
days.
It's -- legendary coach -- who
led the wild cats their first
title 31 years ago obviously
could not be prouder.
Coach Wright on the other hand
played it cool.
Just turned around and shook
hands.
Like nothing happened.
So, but I know inside he was
pretty excited.
So this is a team for the ages
on and off the court.
They ranked in the top 10%
nationally with the grades.
[ APPLAUSE ]
Seniors graduated -- since the
1970s the wild cats have
graduated every four year player
and that is the kind of record
that you really want.
They are also involved in the
Philadelphia community.
Serveing meals for those in need
.
Supporting the special olympics.
Arch and the chef heard about
fan a small boy battleing cancer
who could use a boost and they
snuck into the boy's basement
and hid in his play house to
surprise him which seems a
little scary.
But their hearts were in the
right place.
And that is what we saw all year
from this team.
The heart of a champion.
Congratulations to the wild cats
for an unbelievable season and
with that let me give the podium
to coach Wright.
[ APPLAUSE ]
&gt;&gt; Mr. President, after the
championship we had a big press
conference but nothing as big as
this.
This is a lot of cameras.
This is big time and on behalf
of our entire nova family I want
to thank you and your staff for
inviting us to the White House.
This is a great day for
Villinova university and you
invited the politicians and
everyone connected to Villanova.
Thank you for doing that.
And your staff has been
incredible to us.
You're a great leader and we
want two of our leaders Ryan --
and Daniel to share with you the
jersey 44th president of the
United States.
That we wore this year at Pearl
harbor.
And it was on Pearl harbor day
and we really want to thank you
and it says on there for your
great leadership and your
service to our country.
You're a great role model for
our young men and we thank you
for every thing that do you for
our country and we welcome you
to the nova nation with your
villagersy.
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
-- -- with your Villanova jersey
jersey.
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
[ APPLAUSE ]
&gt;&gt; Fantastic.
Thank you so much.